JON SHOENIG

Washington, DC area

Email: <u>Jonsho25@gmail.com</u> Portfolio: <u>www.jonshoenig.com</u>

Junior Web Developer with Section 508 accessibility background

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A Junior Web Developer eager to grow and expand front-end development skills by creating and modifying websites, recently completed a web development boot camp program while employed as a Section 508 subject matter expert contractor with the Department of Homeland Security's Office of Accessibility Systems and Technology, over 3 years experience testing and fixing Microsoft Office and PDF documents for Section 508 accessibility, serves as lead contractor on Document Accessibility team, self-taught video and audio editor having completed video projects used for Department of Homeland Security trainings

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5 JQuery Section 508 accessibility Git
CSS Bootstrap AJAX Github
Javascript Ruby on Rails Angular-JS Heroku

EDUCATION & TRAINING

CareerFoundry.com- Berlin, Germany

Degree: Certificate in Web Development- November 2015- May 2016

City University of New York - John Jay College, New York, New York

Degree: Master of Arts – Psychology

Boston University, Boston, Massachusetts

Degree: Bachelor of Arts – Psychology and Sociology

CORE COMPETENCIES

Excellent Client Management skills
Consistently Meets or Exceeds Expectations
Outstanding Written and Communication Skills
Works Collaboratively or Independently

Exceptional Interpersonal Skills
Highly Organized and Detail Oriented
Goal and Deadline Driven
Problem Solver/Solutions Focused

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

New Editions Consulting - Falls Church, Virginia

(Contractor at Department of Homeland Security Office of Accessible Systems & Technology: DHS OAST)

Accessibility Technician: February 2015 – Present

Jr. Accessibility Technician: July 2012 – January 2015

- Review and fix Microsoft Office and Adobe PDF documents for Section 508 accessibility
- Create Section 508 accessible fillable forms in PDF format
- Provide technical guidance in layman terms about how to fix documents for Section 508 accessibility
- Serve as lead contractor on Documents team; manage a queue of requests, delegate assignments, and provide guidance to team members
- Perform various administrative functions as needed, often on short notice, per client demand

JON SHOENIG

Page 2

- Collect, organize, and interpret data from the DHS component agencies into high-level reports for DHS senior management including the Chief Information Officer
- Manage the DHS Accessibility Helpdesk; respond to all emails within 2 hours of receipt including answering technical questions about Section 508 accessibility standards
- Train and develop Junior Accessibility Technician team members on job duties, Section 508 document accessibility technical expertise, and client expectations
- Provide video and audio editing services to customer projects as needed

Significant Accomplishments Include:

- 1. Fixing over 1000 PDF and Microsoft documents for Section 508 accessibility including time sensitive, high priority documents requested by the Office of the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security, members of Congress, and the White House
- 2. Creating and editing two videos currently used in monthly Department of Homeland Security employee training sessions
- 3. Managing the DHS Blue Campaign documents project from start to finish by communicating regularly with the customer, delegating documents to team members as well as assigning some to myself, following up on their progress, and providing the customer with a final deliverable prior to the deadline
- 4. Creating an intake form for customers requesting Section 508 accessibility services for electronic documents
- 5. Improving customer service at customer site by managing Helpdesk operations responded to over 500 service requests a week within 2 hours of receipt

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE:

Independence Now, Inc. – Silver Spring, Maryland Community Work Incentive Coordinator: December 2011 – July 2012

Compass Inc. – Beltsville, Maryland Individual Benefits Coordinator: January 2010 – December 2011

Family Services Inc. (formerly Guide Program) – Lanham, Maryland Psychiatric Rehabilitation Specialist: April 2008 – December 2009

Fairfax County Government: Community Services Board (Crisis Care Program) – Annandale, Virginia Mental Health Therapist: September 2005 – January 2008

OTHER COMPUTER SKILLS:

Microsoft Office, Adobe Acrobat, Quickbooks Online, Mac OS